<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Mindful Miles</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Mindful Miles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Journey Through the Sacred Highlands of North Toraja</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/short-cycling-trip-from-center-to-southern-point-of-indonesia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/short-cycling-trip-from-center-to-southern-point-of-indonesia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#quick-summary&#34;&gt;Quick Summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Was not sure about th ejourney due to some erruption (research and give empathetic message) and metion about the chalennege living in Indonesia, a ring of fire country.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Encounter with kids and people, got asked too many times, learing to handle better despote how tiring it was&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Getting Around PELNI Journey and Ferry Journey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Maumere Part and sroty long cycling to Larantuka (Hightlight: Being called &amp;ldquo;Paman&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fell in love with Larntuka&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shipping bicycle around Indonesia using Indah Logistik (reliable and affordeable option)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-do&#34;&gt;TO DO&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Prepare pictures&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Maybe edited maps the journey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Key takeway&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Linking to Packing Panic Projects&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Hinting the Lelunga Project&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;short-summarry&#34;&gt;Short Summarry&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;KM Siguntang to Maumere&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;125 Km Cyling from Maumere to Larantuka&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Crossing with KM Tidar to Kupang&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Explore Kupang&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Crossing to Pulau Rote&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thinking wether to end the trip or stay around Kupang/Rote or even going to far eastern (Ambon)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-insights&#34;&gt;Some insights&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Seeing how different background people unite in a journey together&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tips: never believe the unofficial porter that want to be paid too much&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;eye-opening-regarding-porters&#34;&gt;Eye-opening regarding porters&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;quick-summary&#34;&gt;Quick Summary&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Commuting around Makassar 25 Km&#xA;18 Hours Ship Journey from Makassar to Maumere (KM Siguntang)&#xA;Commuting around Maumere 30 Km&#xA;125 Long day cycling from Maumere to Larantuka&#xA;Commuting around Larantuka 20 Km&#xA;13 hours ship journey from Makassar to Larantuka ()&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mindful Miles</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/about-mindful-miles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/about-mindful-miles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has started with my personal issues, having too crowded mind, I have alwayas felt that there are too many noises in my head.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My personal goal to live more mindfully were more challenging due to issue with my screentime myself. Mindless scrolling made it more noises.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the same time, my love for travelling have led me to different places, that some encounters with people, places nad moments deserve a proper record, especialy for myself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Day Treks Around Pokhara, Nepal, to Do Independently</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/one-day-treks-around-pokhara-nepal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/one-day-treks-around-pokhara-nepal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pokhara, the tourism capital of Nepal, is a trekker&amp;rsquo;s paradise. Nestled in a valley surrounded by the majestic Annapurna mountain range, this city offers easy access to some of the most breathtaking natural scenery in the world. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a taste of adventure without the commitment of a multi-day trek, Pokhara has plenty of options for short, one-day treks that can be done independently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, I like to recommend three great treks that can be done in a single day. The starting and ending points for these treks are relatively easy to reach from the tourist area of Pokhara. Some can be reached by a public bus. Have fun reading and hopefully see you at the treks soon!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embarking Independently: A Comprehensive Guide to Packing for Annapurna Base Camp Trek</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/packing-for-annapurna-base-camp-trek/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/packing-for-annapurna-base-camp-trek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Embarking on an &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/posts/annapurna-base-camp-trek/&#34;&gt;independent trek to the Annapurna Base Camp&lt;/a&gt; is a journey that promises not only breathtaking landscapes but also a profound sense of self-discovery. Unlike guided treks, shouldering the responsibility of your gear adds a unique layer to the adventure. In this comprehensive guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the essentials for a successful and enjoyable trek, based on our recent experience, with a keen focus on practicality and comfort.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Packing List&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Lesson Learned from the Packing List&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Other important things to keep in mind&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;packing-list&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#packing-list&#34;&gt;Packing List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Previously, we published articles about &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/posts/conquering-mount-rinjani/&#34;&gt;hiking in Rinjani&lt;/a&gt; and provided &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/posts/packing-for-rinjani/&#34;&gt;a packing list for that trek&lt;/a&gt;. However, trekking in Annapurna Base Camp offers a completely different experience. During this trek, we&amp;rsquo;ll be spending most nights in guest houses that provide comfortable beds and blankets. One notable difference is that we won&amp;rsquo;t need to carry food, as we can conveniently purchase meals at the restaurants owned by these guest houses along the way. It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that the prices at these higher-altitude restaurants may be on the steeper side. For a breakdown of spending, refer to our previous article: Annapurna Base Camp Trek.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5-Day, 4-Night Annapurna Base Camp Trek—Mastering Independent Exploration with Comprehensive Preparation</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/annapurna-base-camp-trek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/annapurna-base-camp-trek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Embarking on a self-guided trek with friends in the Annapurna region is more than a journey; it&amp;rsquo;s a personal odyssey filled with shared moments and breathtaking landscapes. In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my personal motivations for choosing this unique adventure, guide you through practical aspects such as arranging transportation to Pokhara and acquiring permits independently, provide a cost breakdown, and ensure a safe and memorable trekking experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#trekking-in-nepal&#34;&gt;Trekking in Nepal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#current-possibilities&#34;&gt;Current Possibilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#planning-out-transportations&#34;&gt;Planning out transportations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#arraning-permit-acquisition&#34;&gt;Arranging permit acquisition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#organizing-the-trekking-route-and-securing-guest-house-accommodations&#34;&gt;Organizing the Trekking Route and Securing Guest House Accommodations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#cost-breakdown&#34;&gt;Cost Breakdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#a-recommended-activity-in-pokhara-apart-from-trekking&#34;&gt;A recommended activity in Pokhara apart from trekking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;trekking-in-nepal&#34;&gt;Trekking in Nepal&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nepal, cradled in the embrace of the Himalayas, stands as a trekking haven, seamlessly blending awe-inspiring landscapes with profound cultural immersion. The trails wind through living histories, guiding trekkers through ancient villages and diverse communities. From the lush terraced fields to the serene alpine meadows, Nepal&amp;rsquo;s vistas etch an indelible mark on the soul. Beyond being a mere physical endeavor, trekking in Nepal unfolds as a spiritual journey, with fluttering prayer flags and ancient monasteries creating an ethereal ambiance. The allure of Nepal&amp;rsquo;s trekking extends across all levels, offering challenges like the iconic Everest Base Camp and cultural odysseys through Annapurna, catering to diverse aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Mount Rinjani: A Checklist of Equipment for an Unforgettable Adventure!</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/packing-for-rinjani/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/packing-for-rinjani/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After completing an epic trek on Mount Rinjani, I returned with a sense of happiness and unforgettable memories. The magnificent scenery, lush nature, and the thrill of reaching the summit all became part of my challenging and wondrous journey.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Careful planning was key to ensuring the smooth and joyful progress of my expedition. The packing list played a vital role in my adventure, and I made sure to bring all the necessary equipment to ensure a safe and enjoyable journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conquering Mount Rinjani: A Journey of Majestic Heights and Breathtaking Beauty of West Nusa Tenggara</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/conquering-mount-rinjani/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/conquering-mount-rinjani/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Several times I had plans to experience the thrill of conquering the second highest mountain in Indonesia, and finally, after previous failed attempts, in the second week of July 2023, I had the opportunity to enjoy the beauty of Mount Rinjani in West Nusa Tenggara Province, Indonesia, with my friends.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, I will share my personal preparations before embarking on the hike, information about the journey to Lombok, my experience with registration and collaboration with local guides and porters, profound impressions during the ascent, and other alternative tourist spots to visit while in Lombok.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Bagging Updates 2023 Issue 1</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/one-bagging-updates-2023-issue-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/one-bagging-updates-2023-issue-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a summary of discussions and the latest news in the One Bagger and Light Traveller&amp;rsquo;s space from the last two weeks. From a story of a 70-year-old hiker&amp;rsquo;s 3-week journey in Japan, to tips for staying fit while travelling, even alternatives to Merino t-shirts - we&amp;rsquo;ve got it all covered. So, let&amp;rsquo;s dive in!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#packing-tips-3-weeks-hiking-in-japan&#34;&gt;3 Weeks Hiking in Japan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#packing-tips-dont-overthink-it&#34;&gt;Don&#39;t Overthink to pack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#travel-tip-hard-lesson-from-camping-trip&#34;&gt;Hard Lesson From Camping Trip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#travel-tip-staying-fit-during-long-term-travel&#34;&gt;Staying Fit During Long-Term Travel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#underutilised-digital-nomad-spaces&#34;&gt;Underutilised Digital Nomad Spaces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#gear-digital-nomad-setup&#34;&gt;Digital Nomad Setup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#gear-best-non-merino-travel-t-shirt&#34;&gt;Best Non-merino Travel T-shirts for Men&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#gear-osprey-266-a-brief-review&#34;&gt;Osprey 26+6: A Brief Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;rsquo;s unpack the wealth of information and discover what&amp;rsquo;s been buzzing!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/longest-goodbye-the-playlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/longest-goodbye-the-playlist/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
